I'm a painter.
أنا رسامة.
I make large-scale figurative paintings,
أرسم صورًا رمزيّة كبيرة،
which means I paint people
مما يعني أنني أرسم أناسًا.
like this.
كهذه.
But I'm here tonight to tell you about something personal
لكنني هنا الليلة لأخبركم عن شيءٍ شخصي،
that changed my work and my perspective.
غيّر عملي ومنظوري.
It's something we all go through,
شيء مررنا به جميعًا.
and my hope is that my experience may be helpful to somebody.
وما أتمناه أن تكون خبرتي عونًا لأحدهم.
To give you some background on me, I grew up the youngest of eight.
ولأعطيكم خلفيةً عنّي، كنتُ الصغرى لثمانية.
Yes, eight kids in my family.
أجل، ثمانية أطفال في عائلتي.
I have six older brothers and a sister.
لديّ ستة إخوة كبار، وأخت.
To give you a sense of what that's like,
ولتكونوا مدركين لمعنى ذلك،
when my family went on vacation,
عندما ذهبت عائلتي في عطلة،
we had a bus.
كان لدينا حافلة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
My supermom would drive us all over town
وكانت أمي تقود بنا حول البلدة
to our various after-school activities --
إلى نشاطات ما بعد المدرسة،
not in the bus.
ليس في الحافلة.
We had a regular car, too.
كنا نملك سيارة عادية أيضا.
She would take me to art classes,
كانت تأخذني لدروس الفن.
and not just one or two.
ليس لواحد أو إثنان،
She took me to every available art class from when I was eight to 16,
بل كانت تأخذني لكل الدروس المتوفرة منذ أن كنت في الثامنة حتى 16.
because that's all I wanted to do.
لأن هذا كل ما أردت فعله.
She even took a class with me in New York City.
لدرجة أنها أخذت درسًا معي في نيويورك.
Now, being the youngest of eight, I learned a few survival skills.
والآن، كوني الصغرى لثمانية، تعلمت بعض مهارات النجاة.
Rule number one:
القاعدة الأولى:
don't let your big brother see you do anything stupid.
لا تدع أخاك الأكبر يراك تفعل أي شيءٍ غبي.
So I learned to be quiet and neat
لذلك تعلمت أن أكون هادئة وناعمة.
and careful to follow the rules and stay in line.
ومهتمةً باتباع القوانين والبقاء مركزة.
But painting was where I made the rules.
لكن الرسم هو المكان الذي بنيت فيه القوانين.
That was my private world.
كان هذا عالمي الخاص.
By 14, I knew I really wanted to be an artist.
ببلوغي 14، عرفت أنني أريد أن أصبح فنانة.
My big plan was to be a waitress to support my painting.
كانت خطتي الكبرى أن أصبح نادلة، كي أدعم رسمي.
So I continued honing my skills.
لذلك استمريت بنحت مهاراتي.
I went to graduate school and I got an MFA,
تخرجت وحصلت على ماجستير الفنون الجميلة،
and at my first solo show, my brother asked me,
وفي أول عرض منفردٍ لي، سألني أخي:
"What do all these red dots mean next to the paintings?"
"ما الذي تعنيه هذه النقاط الحمراء بجانب اللوحات؟"
Nobody was more surprised than me.
لم يكن أحد متفاجئًا أكثر مني.
The red dots meant that the paintings were sold
كانت النقاط الحمراء تعني أن اللوحات قد بيعت،
and that I'd be able to pay my rent
وأنني سأكون قادرةً على دفع الإيجار
with painting.
بفضل الرسم.
Now, my apartment had four electrical outlets,
كان في شقتي أربعة منافذ للكهرباء،
and I couldn't use a microwave and a toaster at the same time,
ولم أكن قادرةً على استخدام المايكرويف والمحمصة في الوقت ذاته،
but still, I could pay my rent.
ومع ذلك، كنتُ قادرةً على دفع الإيجار.
So I was very happy.
لذلك كنتُ سعيدة جدا.
Here's a painting from back around that time.
هذه رسمة من تلك الفترة.
I needed it to be as realistic as possible.
أردتها أن تكون واقعيّة بقدر الإمكان.
It had to be specific and believable.
توجّب أن تكون دقيقة ومعقولة.
This was the place where I was isolated and in total control.
كنتُ منعزلة ومتحكمة في هذا المكان.
Since then, I've made a career of painting people in water.
منذ ذلك الحين، جعلتُ من رسمي للناس على الماء مهنةً لي.
Bathtubs and showers were the perfect enclosed environment.
كانت أحواض الاستحمام والدش البيئة المنعزلة المناسبة.
It was intimate and private,
كانت عاطفية وشخصية.
and water was this complicated challenge that kept me busy for a decade.
وكان الماء التحدي المعقد الذي أبقاني منشغلةً لعقدٍ من القرن.
I made about 200 of these paintings,
رسمتُ ما يقارب الـ200 لوحة كهذه.
some of them six to eight feet,
كان البعض منها من 6 إلى 8 أقدام.
like this one.
كهذه.
For this painting, I mixed flour in with the bathwater to make it cloudy
لهذه اللوحة، مزجت الدقيق مع الماء كي أجعلها غير واضحة.
and I floated cooking oil on the surface
ونثرتُ زيت الطبخ على سطحها
and stuck a girl in it,
ووضعت فتاةً فيها،
and when I lit it up,
وحينما رفعتها،
it was so beautiful I couldn't wait to paint it.
كانت في غاية الجمال لم أستطع الانتظار لرسمها.
I was driven by this kind of impulsive curiosity,
كنتُ مدفوعة بهذا النوع من الفضول المتسرع،
always looking for something new to add:
دائمًا ما أبحث عن جديدٍ لأضيفه:
vinyl, steam, glass.
فينيل، بخار، زجاج.
I once put all this Vaseline in my head and hair
في إحدى المرات وضعتُ الكثير من الفازلين على شعرين
just to see what that would look like.
فقط كي أرى كيف سيبدو.
Don't do that.
لا تفعلوا هذا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So it was going well.
كانت الأمور تسير على ما يرام.
I was finding my way.
كنت أجد طريقي.
I was eager and motivated
كنتُ متلهفةً ومندفعة
and surrounded by artists,
ومحاطةً بفنانين،
always going to openings and events.
دائمًا ما أذهب للحفلات والافتتاحات.
I was having some success and recognition
كنت أحظى بالتوفيق والتقدير
and I moved into an apartment with more than four outlets.
وانتقلت لشقةٍ تحوي أكثر من أربعة منافذ.
My mom and I would stay up very late
كنتَ أبقى مع والدتي لوقتٍ متأخر
talking about our latest ideas and inspiring each other.
نتحدث عن آخر أفكارنا ونلهم بعضنا البعض.
She made beautiful pottery.
صنعَت آنية فخارية جميلة.
I have a friend named Bo who made this painting
لديّ صديقٌ اسمه (بو) رسم لوحة
of his wife and I dancing by the ocean,
لي أنا وزوجته نرقص قرب المحيط،
and he called it "The Light Years."
وأسماها (السنين النيّرة).
I asked him what that meant, and he said,
سألته عن معنى ذلك، فقال:
"Well, that's when you've stepped into adulthood, you're no longer a child,
"حسنا، هنا حيث تخطو لسن البلوغ، لم تعد طفلًا بعد الآن،
but you're not yet weighed down by the responsibilities of life."
لكن مسؤوليّات الحياة لم تتعبك بعد."
That was it. It was the light years.
هذه كانت السنين النيّرة.
On October 8, 2011,
في 8 أكتوبر 2011،
the light years came to an end.
وصلت السنين النيّرة إلى نهايتها.
My mom was diagnosed with lung cancer.
تم تشخيص أمي بسرطان الرئة.
It had spread to her bones, and it was in her brain.
كان قد انتشر في عظامها، ووصل إلى دماغها.
When she told me this, I fell to my knees.
حينما أخبرتني بذلك، جثوت على ركبتيّ.
I totally lost it.
خسرتها تماما.
And when I got myself together and I looked at her,
وحينما استجمعت نفسي، ونظرتُ إليها،
I realized, this isn't about me.
أدركت أنه ليس عنّي.
This is about figuring out how to help her.
بل عن معرفة كيفيّة مساعدتها.
My father is a doctor,
كان والدي دكتورا،
and so we had a great advantage having him in charge,
لذلك فقد كان من مصلحتنا أنه المسؤول،
and he did a beautiful job taking care of her.
فقد قام بعملٍ جميل بالاعتناء بها.
But I, too, wanted to do everything I could to help,
لكنني بدوري أردت فعل ما بوسعي للمساعدة،
so I wanted to try everything.
لذلك أردت تجربة كل شيء.
We all did.
جميعنا فعلنا.
I researched alternative medicines,
بحثتُ عن أدوية بديلة،
diets, juicing, acupuncture.
من أغذية، وعصائر، وأبر.
Finally, I asked her,
في النهاية، سألتها:
"Is this what you want me to do?"
"أهذا ما تريديني أن أفعله؟"
And she said, "No."
فقالت: "لا".
She said, "Pace yourself. I'm going to need you later."
قالت: "أسرعي بنفسك. سأحتاجكِ لاحقا."
She knew what was happening,
كانت على علمٍ بما يحدث،
and she knew what the doctors
كانت تعرف ما لم يعرفه الأطباء
and the experts and the internet didn't know:
والخبراء، والإنترنت.
how she wanted to go through this.
كيف تريد أن تمر بهذا.
I just needed to ask her.
احتجت فقط لأن أسألها.
I realized that if I tried to fix it,
أدركتُ أنني إن حاولت إصلاحه،
I would miss it.
سأخطئ.
So I just started to be with her,
لذلك بدأت بأن أكون معها
whatever that meant and whatever situation came up,
أيّا كان يعنيه ذلك، وأيّما ظرفٍ يطرأ،
just really listen to her.
أن أستمع لها حقا.
If before I was resisting, then now I was surrendering,
إن كنتُ من قبل أقاوم، فقد أصبحتُ الآن أستسلم،
giving up trying to control the uncontrollable
يائسةً من محاولة السيطرة على ما لا قدرة لي عليه
and just being there in it with her.
وأن أكون معها في ذلك.
Time slowed down,
بدأ الوقت بالتباطؤ،
and the date was irrelevant.
ولم يكن للتاريخ علاقة.
We developed a routine.
طوّرنا روتينًا.
Early each morning I would crawl into bed with her and sleep with her.
باكرًا في كل صباح كنت أذهب للسرير معها وأنام.
My brother would come for breakfast
كان أخي يأتي للفطور
and we'd be so glad to hear his car coming up the driveway.
وكنا نسعد جدا بسماع صوت سيارته قادمةً من على الطريق.
So I'd help her up and take both her hands
لذا فقد كنتُ أساعدها للنهوض وآخذ بيديها
and help her walk to the kitchen.
وأساعدها على المشي إلى المطبخ.
She had this huge mug she made
كان لديها هذا الكوب الكبير الذي صنعته
she loved to drink her coffee out of,
كانت تحب شرب قهوتها منه،
and she loved Irish soda bread for breakfast.
وكانت تحب خبز الصودا الإيرلندية على الفطور.
Afterwards was the shower,
بعد ذلك يأتي الاستحمام،
and she loved this part.
وقد أحبت هذا الجزء.
She loved the warm water,
أحبت الماء الدافئ،
so I made this as indulgent as I could,
لذا فقد قمت بذلك متساهلةً بقدر الإمكان،
like a spa.
كالمنتجع.
My sister would help sometimes.
كانت أختي تساعد في بعض المرات.
We had warm towels
كان لدينا مناشف دافئة
and slippers ready immediately
وأحذية جاهزة فورا
so she never got cold for a second.
كي لا تبرد ولو للحظة.
I'd blow-dry her hair.
كنت أجفف شعرها.
My brothers would come in the evenings and bring their kids,
كان إخوتي يأتون في المساء ويحضرون أطفالهم.
and that was the highlight of her day.
وكان هذا أهم جزء في يومها.
Over time, we started to use a wheelchair,
بمرور الوقت، بدأنا باستخدام الكرسي المتحرك،
and she didn't want to eat so much,
ولم تكن تريد أن تأكل كثيرا،
and she used the tiniest little teacup we could find to drink her coffee.
وكانت تستخدم أصغر كوب شاي استطعنا أن نجده كي تشرب قهوتها.
I couldn't support her myself anymore,
لم أكن قادرة على مساعدتها لوحدي،
so we hired an aide to help me with the showers.
لذلك أحضرنا معاونًا كي يساعدني في استحمامها.
These simple daily activities
هذه النشاطات اليومية البسيطة
became our sacred ritual,
أصبحت طقوسنا المقدسة،
and we repeated them day after day
وكررناها يومًا بعد يوم
as the cancer grew.
كما كان ينتشر السرطان.
It was humbling and painful
كان وضيعًا ومؤلما
and exactly where I wanted to be.
وتمامًا حيث أردت أن أكون.
We called this time "the beautiful awful."
أسمينا ذلك الوقت "الجميل المروّع".
She died on October 26, 2012.
مات في 26 أكتوبر 2012.
It was a year and three weeks after her diagnosis.
كان سنةً وثلاثة أسابيع بعد تشخيصها.
She was gone.
كانت قد رحلت.
My brothers, sister, and father and I
إخواني وأختي ووالدي وأنا
all came together in this supportive and attentive way.
اجتمعنا بهذه الطريقة الداعمة والمهتمة.
It was as though our whole family dynamic
كانت كأنما فعالية عائلتنا بأكملها
and all our established roles vanished
وجميع أدوارنا المقررة قد اختفت
and we were just all together in this unknown,
وكنا مجتمعين في هذا المجهول،
feeling the same thing
بنفس الشعور
and taking care of each other.
ومهتمين ببعضنا البعض.
I'm so grateful for them.
أنا ممتنة جدا لهم.
As someone who spends most of my time alone in a studio working,
كشخصٍ أقضي أغلب وقتي أعمل في الأستوديو،
I had no idea that this kind of connection
لم يكن لدي فكرة أن هذا النوع من التواصل
could be so important, so healing.
قد يكون مهمًا جدا، جالبا للعافية.
This was the most important thing.
كان هذا أهم شيء.
It was what I always wanted.
كان كل ما أردته يوما.
So after the funeral, it was time for me to go back to my studio.
وبالتالي بعد العزاء، فقد حان وقت عودتي إلى الأستوديو.
So I packed up my car and I drove back to Brooklyn,
لذلك حزمت أغراضي، وعدت إلى (بروكلين)،
and painting is what I've always done, so that's what I did.
الرسم هو كل ما أفعله، لذا هذا ما فعلته.
And here's what happened.
وهذا ما حدث.
It's like a release of everything that was unraveling in me.
هو كإطلاق كل شيءٍ كان غير مربوط بي.
That safe, very, very carefully rendered safe place
هذا المكان الآمن جدا
that I created in all my other paintings,
الذي خلقته في جميع رسوماتي الأخرى،
it was a myth.
كان خرافة.
It didn't work.
لم ينفع.
And I was afraid, because I didn't want to paint anymore.
وكنتُ خائفة؛ لأنني لم أرد الرسم بعد الآن.
So I went into the woods.
لذلك ذهبت للغابة.
I thought, I'll try that, going outside.
اعتقدت أنني سأحاول ذلك، محاولة الذهاب خارجا.
I got my paints, and I wasn't a landscape painter,
أخذت رسوماتي، ولم أكن رسامة للطبيعة،
but I wasn't really much of any kind of painter at all,
لكنني لم أكن فعلا أي نوعٍ من الرسامين على الإطلاق،
so I had no attachment, no expectation,
لذا لم يكن لدي أي ارتباطات أو توقعات،
which allowed me to be reckless and free.
والذي مكنني من أن أكون مجازفة وحرة.
I actually left one of these wet paintings
في الحقيقة تركت أحد هذه الرسومات المبللة
outside overnight
خارجًا حتى الصباح
next to a light in the woods.
بالقرب من المصباح في الغابة.
By the morning it was lacquered with bugs.
بحلول الصباح كانت مطلية بالحشرات.
But I didn't care. It didn't matter. It didn't matter.
لكنني لم أهتم. لم يكن مهما.
I took all these paintings back to my studio,
أعدت كل هذه الرسومات إلى الأستوديو،
and scraped them, and carved into them,
وقشّرتها ونحتّها،
and poured paint thinner on them,
وطليتها بشكلٍ افضل،
put more paint on top, drew on them.
وضعت المزيد من الطلاء، وأعدت رسمها،
I had no plan,
لم أكن أعرف ما أفعل،
but I was watching what was happening.
لكنني كنت أتابع ما يحدث.
This is the one with all the bugs in it.
هذه اللوحة التي أتت عليها الحشرات.
I wasn't trying to represent a real space.
لم أكن أحاول رسم مساحةٍ حقيقية.
It was the chaos and the imperfections that were fascinating me,
كانت العيوب والفوضى هي التي تسحرني،
and something started to happen.
وبدأ شيء ما بالحدوث.
I got curious again.
انتابني الفضول مجددا.
This is another one from the woods.
هذه لوحة أخرى من الغابة.
There was a caveat now, though.
هناك الآن مذكرة عليها الآن.
I couldn't be controlling the paint like I used to.
لم أكن قادرة على التحكم بالرسم كما كنت.
It had to be about implying and suggesting,
توجّب أن تكون عن التخمين والتوقع،
not explaining or describing.
ليس عن الشرح أو الوصف.
And that imperfect, chaotic, turbulent surface
وهذا النقص والفوضى والعنف
is what told the story.
هو ما روى القصة.
I started to be as curious as I was when I was a student.
بدأ يأتيني الفضول كحينما كنت طالبة.
So the next thing was I wanted to put figures in these paintings, people,
لذا كان الشيء التالي الذي أردت فعله هو وضع التفاصيل على الرسومات والأشخاص،
and I loved this new environment,
لقد أحببت تلك البيئة،
so I wanted to have both people and this atmosphere.
لذلك أردت أن أحظى بكليهما، الناس وهذا الجو.
When the idea hit me of how to do this,
عندما أتتني فكرة كيفية عمل هذا،
I got kind of nauseous and dizzy,
أتاني نوعٌ من التشوش والدوران،
which is really just adrenaline, probably,
والذي في الغالب مجرد أدرينالين،
but for me it's a really good sign.
ولكن بالنسبة لي فهو علامة جيدة.
And so now I want to show you what I've been working on.
والآن، أريد أريكم ما كنتُ اعمل عليه.
It's something I haven't shown yet, and it's like a preview, I guess,
شيء لم أظهره بعد، إلقاء نظرة أظن
of my upcoming show,
لعرضي القادم،
what I have so far.
ما لدي حتى الآن.
Expansive space
مساحة واسعة
instead of the isolated bathtub.
بدلا من الحوض المنعزل.
I'm going outside instead of inside.
ذاهبة للخارج بدلا من الداخل.
Loosening control,
أفقد السيطرة،
savoring the imperfections,
أعاني النقصان،
allowing the --
سامحة للـ...
allowing the imperfections.
سامحة للعيوب.
And in that imperfection,
وفي تلك العيوب،
you can find a vulnerability.
ستجد الحساسية.
I could feel my deepest intention, what matters most to me,
استطعت الشعور بأعمق نواياي، ما يهمني بشكل أكبر،
that human connection
هذا التواصل البشري
that can happen in a space where there's no resisting or controlling.
الذي قد يحدث في مكانٍ خالٍ من المقاومة والهيمنة.
I want to make paintings about that.
أردت رسم لوحات عن ذلك.
So here's what I learned.
لذا هذا ما تعلمته.
We're all going to have big losses in our lives,
جيمعنا سنخسر خسائر فادحة في حياتنا،
maybe a job or a career,
ربما وظيفة او تقدم،
relationships, love, our youth.
علاقات، حب، شبابنا.
We're going to lose our health,
جميعنا سنخسر صحّتنا.
people we love.
الناس الذين نحبهم.
These kinds of losses are out of our control.
هذه النوع من الخسائر خارج عن السيطرة.
They're unpredictable,
لا يمكن التنبؤ بها،
and they bring us to our knees.
وتجعلنا نجثو على أقدامنا.
And so I say, let them.
وكما قلت، دعوها تفعل.
Fall to your knees. Be humbled.
اجثو على قدميك. كن ذليلا.
Let go of trying to change it
دع عنك محاولة تغييرها
or even wanting it to be different.
أو حتى تمني أن تكون مختلفة.
It just is.
هي هكذا فحسب.
And then there's space,
وبعد ذلك، هناك تلك المساحة،
and in that space feel your vulnerability,
وفي تلك المساحة، اشعر بحساسيتك،
what matters most to you,
ما يهمك بشكلٍ أكبر،
your deepest intention.
أعمق أهدافك.
And be curious to connect
وكن فضوليا للتواصل
to what and who is really here,
لأي شيء هنالك حقا،
awake and alive.
مستيقظ وحي.
It's what we all want.
هذا ما نريده جميعا.
Let's take the opportunity to find something beautiful
دعونا نأخذ فرصة إيجاد شيء جميل
in the unknown, in the unpredictable,
في المجهول، في غير المتوقع،
and even in the awful.
وحتى في الفظيع.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)